LION BEHRENS

June 2018

★ lionbehrens.netlify.com ★@LionBehrens \square behrens@uni-mannheim.de \+49 621 181-3441 University of Mannheim, B6 30-32, Room 338, 68131 Mannheim, Germany

SUMMARY

I am an early career academic researching comparative politics and quantitative methods. In my methodical work, I explore the merits that Bayesian statistics provides for inference in the political sciences, particularly when facing challenges such as evidence synthesis and multi-method research. Within comparative politics, my work primarily centers around questions of political behavior, focusing both on citizens' actions and expectations as well as legislators' reactions and output.

CURRENT POSITION

June 2018 - ongoing Research Associate

Collaborative Research Center 884, University of Mannheim

Project C7 "Political attention and the substance of legislative reform"

EDUCATION

Ph.D. Political Science Sep 2018 - ongoing

Graduate School of Economic and Social Sciences, University of Mannheim

M.Sc. Methodology and Statistics Sep 2016 - May 2018

Utrecht University

Grade Average: 7.90/10.00

B.A. Political Science Sep 2013 - July 2016

University of Bremen

Grade Average: 1.09, with distinction

PEER-REVIEWED PUBLICATIONS

Behrens, Lion and Ingo Rohlfing. 2018. "Not so different in present attitudes and behavior, but expected future membership - A technical replication of a study of party youth in six European democracies". Research & Politics, Online Only, 1-5.

WORK IN PROGRESS

Behrens, Lion and Rebecca M Kuiper. "A Bayesian method for synthesizing evidence from heterogeneous statistical models". Working Paper.

Behrens, Lion and Ingo Rohlfing. "Bayesian nested analysis". In preparation.

Buskens, Vincent, Werner Raub, Lion Behrens, Rebecca M. Kuiper and Irene Klugkist. "Embeddedness effects on trust in social and economic exchange: A Bayesian analysis of evidence from four studies". In preparation.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant

Applied Bayesian Statistics, Utrecht Summer School

July 2017 Structural Equation Modeling with Mplus, Utrecht Summer School March 2017 - May 2017

Business Statistics, De Bijlespartner Amsterdam

May 2018

Tutor

Instrumental Variables in Psychology, B.A. Thesis, Utrecht University, by Hugo Hanema

January 2017 - May 2017

PRESENTATIONS

"Political Trust and Political Participation - The Micro-Level Relationship and Its Macro-Level Dependencies", Semiannual Meeting of the Ecuadorian Political Science Association (AECIP), Quito April 2016

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Internships

GESIS - Leibniz Institute for the Social Sciences, Mannheim

January - March 2018

Research assistance for Oshrat Hochman analyzing European Social Survey data

FLACSO - Latin American Social Science Institute, Quito

February - April 2016

Research on political participation analyzing data from the Latin American Public Opinion Project

Research Assistantships

Department for Methods & Statistics, Utrecht University, Prof. Rens van de Schoot, Ph.D. Jan 17 - March 18
Bremen International Graduate School of Social Sciences, Prof. Ingo Rohlfing, Ph.D. April - July 2016
Research Center on Inequality and Social Policy, Bremen, Prof. Michael Windzio March - August 2015
Collaborative Research Center 597, Bremen University, Natascha Zaun, Ph.D. July - December 2014

GRANTS AND SCHOLARSHIPS

Full scholarship grant, Studienstiftung des deutschen Volkes	2016 - 2018
Full scholarship grant, Konrad-Adenauer-Stiftung	2013 - 2016

ADDITIONAL TRAINING

Multilevel analysis using HLM, Training course, GESIS L	eibniz Institute for the Social Sciences 201	15
Advanced Programming in R, Coursera MOOC, John Ho	pkins University 201	17

INVITED REFEREE

Research & Politics

SKILLS

Computing

R, Stata, Mplus, SPSS, HLM, JAGS, Shiny, LATEX, Markdown

Methodical

General Linear Model, Multilevel Analysis, Structural Equation Modeling, Instrumental Variables, Propensity Score Matching, Statistical Computing and Simulation, Bayesian Methods

Languages

German: Native, English: Fluent, Spanish: Oral Fluency

REFERENCES

Prof. Ingo Rohlfing, PhD

Center for Comparative Politics

University of Cologne, Germany

Phone: +49 221 470-89104 Email: i.rohlfing@uni-koeln.de

G

Prof. Rens van de Schoot, PhD

Department of Methods and Statistics Utrecht University, The Netherlands

Phone: +31 30 253 4594

Email: A.G.J.vandeSchoot@uu.nl